A Guide to the Foundation Center of New York records FA023
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Non-Related Foundation Center Files, 1947-1990; 3
  - Tax Reform Records, 1947-1990; 2
    Series 3.2 is arranged in three sections:
    A - Cox and Reece Tax Committee Hearings
    B - Tax Reform Act of 1969
    C - Internal Revenue Service, Congressional Hearings from the 1970s-1990
    This series contains files of correspondence, newspaper clippings, a scrapbook, and IRS forms having to do with the changes in the tax system for non-profit organizations.
    - Cox & Reece Tax Committee Hearings, 1947-1955; A
      Series 3.2A includes information about the first of the tax reforms that Congress enacted which affected non-profit organizations.
      - F. Emerson Andrews - Testimony Before the Select Committee to Investigate Tax-Exempt Foundations and Comparable Organizations - House of Representatives, November 18, 1952 (Reel 167, Frame 264)
      - Congressional Questionnaire and Address List, 1952 (Reel 167, Frame 407)
      - Answers to Congressional Questionnaire - Carnegie Corporation of New York, 1952-1954 (Reel 167, Frame 435)
      - Answers to Congressional Questionnaire - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, 1952 (Reel 167, Frame 508)
      - Answers to Congressional Questionnaire - Carnegie Institution of Washington, 1952 (Reel 167, Frame 561)
      - Answers to Congressional Questionnaire - The Cleveland Foundation, 1952 (Reel 167, Frame 696)
      - Answers to Congressional Questionnaire - The Field Foundation, Inc., 1952 (Reel 167, Frame 734)
      - Answers to Congressional Questionnaire - General Education Board, 1952 (Reel 167, Frame 807)
      - Answers to Congressional Questionnaire - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1952 (Reel 167, Frame 946)
      - Answers to Congressional Questionnaire - Louis W. and Maud Hill Family Foundation, 1952 (Reel 168, Frame 1)
      - Answers to Congressional Questionnaire - The Henry J. Kaiser Family Foundation, 1952 (Reel 168, Frame 47)
      - Answers to Congressional Questionnaire - Kate Macy Ladd Fund, 1952 (Reel 168, Frame 81)
      - Answers to Congressional Questionnaire - John and Mary R. Markle Foundation, 1952 (Reel 168, Frame 101)
      - Answers to Congressional Questionnaire - The A. W. Mellon Educational and Charitable Trust, 1952 (Reel 168, Frame 256)
      - Answers to Congressional Questionnaire - New York Community Trust, 1952 (Reel 168, Frame 307)
      - Answers to Congressional Questionnaire - Old Dominion Foundation, Inc., 1952 (Reel 168, Frame 310)
      - Answers to Congressional Questionnaire - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1952 (Reel 168, Frame 377)
      - Answers to Congressional Questionnaire - Russell Sage Foundation, 1952 (Reel 168, Frame 543)
      - Answers to Congressional Questionnaire - Sarah Mellon Scaife Foundation, 1952 (Reel 168, Frame 581)
      - Answers to Congressional Questionnaire - Trexler Foundation, 1952 (Reel 168, Frame 609)
      - Answers to Congressional Questionnaire - Twentieth Century Fund, Inc., 1952 (Reel 168, Frame 628)
      - Additional Views of Angier L. Goodwin, December 16, 1954 (Reel 168, Frame 684)
      - Congressional Record - Proceedings and Debates of the 84th Congress, June 14, 1955 (Reel 168, Frame 690)
      - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1952-1955 (Reel 168, Frame 692)
      - The Ford Foundation - Statement of H. Rowan Gaither, Jr., President and Trustee - Special Committee to Investigate Tax Exempt Foundations - House of Representatives - 83rd Congress, July 16, 1954 (Reel 168, Frame 847)
      - Hearings Before the Committee to Investigate Tax-Exempt Foundations and Comparable Organizations (House Resolution 651), 1952-1953 (Reel 168, Frame 946)
      - Hearings Before the Ways and Means Committee on Income Tax Exemptions, 1947 (Reel 168, Frame 957)
      - Hearings of the Special Committee to Investigate Tax Exempt Foundations (House Resolution 217), 1953-1955 (Reel 168, Frame 975)
      - Report from the Russell Sage Foundation, December 3, 1953 (Reel 168, Frame 977)
      - Rich List - A-Z, undated (Reel 168, Frame 1074)
      - Special Committee on Tax-Exempt Foundations - Speech by Honorable Carroll Reece of Tennessee, August 20, 1954 (Reel 168, Frame 1093)
      - Tax Exempt Application, 1951-1952 (Reel 168, Frame 1095)
      - Treasury List (A-Z), undated (Reel 169, Frame 1)
      - Scrapbook, 1951-1953 (Reel 169, Frame 202)
    - Tax Reform Act of 1969, 1962-1981; B
      Information in Series 3.2B details the second set of actions and changes that Congress made relating to non-profit organizations and their taxation.
      - Commission on Foundations and Private Philanthropy, May 10, 1970 (Reel 169, Frame 299)
      - Conferences on the Tax Reform Act of 1969 - Kansas City, Missouri and New York, New York (Reel 169, Frame 339)
      - Congressional Hearings, 1969 (Reel 169, Frame 471)
      - Federal Register - Part 1, April 2, 1971 (Reel 169, Frame 523)
      - Foundations and the Tax Bill, 1969 (Reel 169, Frame 525)
      - Foundations and the Tax Bill - Testimony on Title I of the Tax Reform Act of 1969 - Submitted by Witnesses Appearing Before the United States Senate Finance Committee (Reel 169, Frame 566)
      - Hartke Subcommittee, 1973-1975 (Reel 169, Frame 682)
      - House Resolutions, 1965-1973 (Reel 169, Frame 840)
      - Internal Revenue Service Tax Reform Act Regulations and New York City Real Estate Tax, 1970-1973 (Reel 169, Frame 843)
      - Marianna O. Lewis - Congressional Tax Reform Act, 1969-1971 (Reel 169, Frame 963)
      - Dick Magats' Materials on Tax Reform Act of 1969 (Reel 170, Frame 1)
      - Memoranda, 1971-1973 (Reel 170, Frame 143)
      - Wright Patman, 1964-1972 (Reel 170, Frame 167)
      - Private Foundations - Hearings Before the Subcommittee on Foundations of the Committee on Finance - United States Senate, 1973-1974 (Reel 170, Frame 201)
      - Senate Resolutions, 1965-1969 (Reel 170, Frame 203)
      - "Speaking Freely" - WNBC Television, January 29, 1968 (Reel 170, Frame 205)
      - Summaries, 1965-1970 (Reel 170, Frame 242)
      - Summary of the Tax Reform Act of 1969 by The Foundation Center, 1970 (Reel 170, Frame 291)
      - Tax Exempt Foundations - Their Impact on Small Business, 1964-1967 (Reel 170, Frame 308)
      - Tax Exempt Foundations and Charitable Trusts - Their Impact on Our Economy, 1962-1972 (Reel 170, Frame 310)
      - Tax Reform Act of 1969 - Clippings, March-September 1969 (Reel 170, Frame 312)
      - Tax Reform Act of 1969 - Clippings, October-December 1969 (Reel 170, Frame 451)
      - Tax Reform Act of 1969 - Clippings, January-April 1970 (Reel 170, Frame 668)
      - Tax Reform Act of 1969 - Clippings, 1969-1974 (Reel 170, Frame 680)
      - Tax Reform Act of 1969 - House Resolution 13270 (Reel 170, Frame 826)
      - Tax Reform Act of 1969 - Miscellaneous - Congressional Record - Memoranda and Press Releases, 1961-1981 (Reel 170, Frame 829)
      - Technical Explanation of Treasury Tax Reform Proposals, April 22, 1969 (Reel 171, Frame 1)
      - Testimonies, 1969-1974 (Reel 171, Frame 223)
      - Treasury Department Report on Private Foundations, 1965 (Reel 171, Frame 276)
      - United States Department of the Treasury - Internal Revenue Service - Transcript of Proceedings, December 7, 1971 (Reel 171, Frame 278)
    - Internal Revenue Service, Congressional Hearings from the 1970s-1990, 1976-1990; C
      Series 3.2C includes material about the third set of tax-related actions taken by Congress against non-profit organizations.
      - Congressional Hearings - Thomas R. Buckman's Statement to the Subcommittee on Taxation and Debt Management, February 24, 1984 (Reel 171, Frame 281)
      - Congressional Hearings - General Accounting Office Study, 1981-1984 (Reel 171, Frame 370)
      - Congressional Hearings - House and Senate, 1983-1984 (Reel 171, Frame 519)
      - Congressional Hearings - House Subcommittee on Commerce - Consumer and Monetary Affairs, 1983 (Reel 171, Frame 645)
      - Congressional Hearings - Witness Statements Before the Subcommittee on Oversight Concerning the Operations and Activities of Private Foundations, June 27, 28 and 30, 1983 (Reel 171, Frame 669)
      - General Accounting Office - Draft of Proposed Report - Public Information Reporting By Tax-Exempt Private Foundations Needs More Attention by IRS, 1982 (Reel 171, Frame 990)
      - Hearing Before the Subcommittee on Government Operations, May 11, 1983 (Reel 171, Frame 1082)
      - Hearing Before the Subcommittee on Oversight of the Committee on Ways and Means, 1983 (Reel 171, Frame 1084)
      - Internal Revenue Service, 1976-1986 (Reel 172, Frame 1)
      - Internal Revenue Service - Aperture Cards Shipping and Delays, 1985-1987 (Reel 172, Frame 263)
      - Internal Revenue Service - Articles, 1989-1990 (Reel 172, Frame 309)
      - Internal Revenue Service - Correspondence, 1983-1990 (Reel 172, Frame 328)
      - Internal Revenue Service - Designation of the Foundation Center, 1977-1980 (Reel 172, Frame 492)
      - Internal Revenue Service - Financial Accounting Standards Board, 1983-1984 (Reel 172, Frame 999)
      - Internal Revenue Service - Form 990 Advisory Committee, 1980-1985 (Reel 173, Frame 1)
      - Internal Revenue Service - Revision of Form 990-PF, 1981-1984 (Reel 173, Frame 441)
      - Internal Revenue Service - Russell Mawby, 1990 (Reel 173, Frame 533)
      - Internal Revenue Service - Meeting in Philadelphia, December 10, 1985 (Reel 173, Frame 544)
      - Internal Revenue Service - Mid-Atlantic Service Center, 1971-1978 (Reel 173, Frame 593)
      - Internal Revenue Service - Systems Modernization Forum, May 30-June 1, 1990 (Reel 173, Frame 616)
      - Report and Recommendations to the Commission on Private Philanthropy and Public Needs on Private Philanthropic Foundations, August 12, 1974 (Reel 173, Frame 752)
      - Statistics of Income Bulletin, Fall 1985 (Reel 173, Frame 907)
- Foundation Center Annual Reports, 1956-2007; 4; 40 Bound Volumes 40 bound volumes
  Series 1: Administration, Subseries 1: Historical Information
  Annual reports
  - Foundation Library Center Annual Report 1956-1961 (Item REF 060 FOU 1956-1961)
  - Foundation Library Center Annual Report 1962-1966 (Item REF 060 FOU 1962-1966)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1967 (Item REF 361.7 FOU 1967)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1968 (Item REF 361.7 FOU 1968)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1969 (Item REF 361.7 FOU 1969)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1970 (Item REF 361.7 FOU 1970)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1971 (Item REF 361.7 FOU 1971)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1972 (Item REF 361.7 FOU 1972)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1973 (Item REF 361.7 FOU 1973)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1974 (Item REF 361.7 FOU 1974)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1975 (Item REF 361.7 FOU 1975)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1976 (Item REF 361.7 FOU 1976)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1977 (Item REF 361.7 FOU 1977)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1978 (Item REF 361.7 FOU 1978)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1979 (Item REF 361.7 FOU 1979)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1980 (Item REF 361.7 FOU 1980)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1981 (Item REF 361.7 FOU 1981)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1982 (Item REF 361.7 FOU 1982)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1983 (Item REF 361.7 FOU 1983)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1984 (Item REF 361.763 FOU 1984)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1985 (Item REF 361.763 FOU 1985)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1986 (Item REF 361.763 FOU 1986)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1987 (Item REF 361.763 FOU 1987)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1988 (Item REF 361.763 1988)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1989 (Item REF 361.763 FOU 1989)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1990 (Item REF 362.763 FOU 1990)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1991 (Item REF 361.763 FOU 1991)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1992 (Item REF 36.763 FOU 1992)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1993 (Item REF 361.763 FOU 1993)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1994 (Item REF 361.763 FOU 1994)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1995 (Item REF 361.763 FOU 1995)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1996 (Item REF 361.763 FOU 1996)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1997 (Item REF 361.763 FOU 1997)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1998 (Item REF 361.7633 FOU 1998)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 1999 (Item REF 361.763 FOU 1999)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 2000 (Item REF 361.763 FOU 2000)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 2001 (Item REF 361.763 FOU 2001)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 2002 (Item REF 361.763 FOU 2002)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 2003 (Item REF 361.763 FOU 2003)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 2004 (Item REF 361.763 FOU 2004)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 2005 (Item REF 361.763 FOU 2005)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 2006 (Item REF 361.763 FOU 2006)
  - Foundation Center Annual Report 2007 (Item REF 361.763 FOU 2007)
- Separated Materials, 5
  Scope and Contents
  Paper records retained by the RAC that were not microfilmed, including reports, photographs, and other items.
  - Separated Materials (Box 1)
  - Separated Materials (Box 2)
  - Separated Materials (Box 3)
  - Separated Materials (Box 4)